<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://gamedevforge.net/blog</id>
    <title>GameDevForge Blog</title>
    <updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog"/>
    <subtitle>GameDevForge Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://gamedevforge.net/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
        <id>https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome</id>
        <link href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome"/>
        <updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to GameDevForge!]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to GameDevForge!</p>
<p>I've played with the idea of creating something along these lines for a while. Originally, I planned for a blog where I would post about useful tips
and tricks I've learned over the years. However, after seeing the knowledge level of a few people fresh out of University, I decided to expand the
idea into a full-blown learning resource for all things game development.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="who-am-i">Who am I?<a href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome#who-am-i" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Who am I?" title="Direct link to Who am I?">​</a></h2>
<p>I'm Lewis, a Senior Game Developer currently working at BULKHEAD. I've been in the industry for around 5 years now and have worked on a variety of
projects ranging from virtual reality training simulations to multiplayer first-person shooters. I have touched on many different areas like gameplay,
networking and systems architecture to name a few but have also had experience planning and leading smaller teams.</p>
<p>At this point in my career, I feel like I have a lot of knowledge to share and I want to help others learn and grow in the industry. I don't doubt that
I will make mistakes or miss out on some key points in areas, but I hope that the community can help me improve and grow this resource.</p>
<p>Find out more about me on <a href="https://lewisscrivens.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">my website</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="who-is-it-for">Who is it For?<a href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome#who-is-it-for" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Who is it For?" title="Direct link to Who is it For?">​</a></h2>
<p>Everyone! In its early state at the writing of this post, there is not a lot of content, especially for anyone already at or above the beginner level.
However, I plan to expand the content to cover a wide range of topics and difficulties as time goes on.</p>
<p>At the moment I am focussing on the modules section, which will be a series of tutorials and resources aiming to take a novice from beginner to
intermediate levels and beyond.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why">Why?<a href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome#why" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why?" title="Direct link to Why?">​</a></h2>
<p>One reason is to help others in general. That being said, I will benefit massively from this project too. Taking what I have
learned over the past 5 years and putting it into writing will help me solidify and document my knowledge. I also hope to learn a lot from the community
interacting with blog posts and tutorials and giving feedback on what can be improved.</p>
<p>There are many resources out there for game development, but I feel like there is a gap in the market for a resource that compiles all the aspects of learning,
research, and development into one place. I want to create a resource that is easy to navigate and understand, up to date with the latest industry knowledge, and
continues to be useful past the beginner level.</p>
<p>Back in my University days, I was lucky enough to have lecturers that really pushed me to learn and understand the core concepts of game development.
From what I have seen recently during interviews and informal chats with fresh graduates, it seems that isn't always the case.</p>
<p>By no means are you supposed to know everything when you leave University, but I feel that there are some core concepts that are being missed. One of the
aims of this website, will be to provide industry knowledge for the expectations of a Junior Game Developer.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whats-the-plan">What's the Plan?<a href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome#whats-the-plan" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to What's the Plan?" title="Direct link to What's the Plan?">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="modules">Modules<a href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome#modules" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Modules" title="Direct link to Modules">​</a></h3>
<p>I have a lot of ideas for this project, but like I mentioned, it is in its early stages.
The modules section will come first which will be broken down into different areas.</p>
<ul>
<li>Java</li>
<li>C++</li>
<li>Unreal Engine</li>
</ul>
<p>These three areas will be broken down further to cover a wide range of topics. Take Java for example, It's purpose on this resource is not to make someone an
expert Java developer, but rather give them a solid base to work from. C++ will be more advanced and tackle more complex topics like 3D rendering and game engine architecture.</p>
<p>From my experience, people want to jump in with a game engine like Unreal Engine or Unity without understanding programming at its core.
This is a big mistake and can put the brakes on learning and development.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="blog">Blog<a href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome#blog" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Blog" title="Direct link to Blog">​</a></h3>
<p>I plan to post as much as possible to this blog, although I imagine it will be quiet for a while during the development of the modules section. The GameDevForge blog is and will
be my main blogging platform.</p>
<p>So expect to see posts from a variety of topics based in and around game development.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="unreal-compendium">Unreal Compendium<a href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome#unreal-compendium" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Unreal Compendium" title="Direct link to Unreal Compendium">​</a></h3>
<p>I plan to write generalised knowledge about systems within Unreal Engine. Inspired from other well know resources and developers like:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cedric-neukirchen.net/docs/category/multiplayer-network-compendium" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cedric Neukirchen's Multiplayer Network Compendium For Unreal Engine</a></li>
<li><a href="https://benui.ca/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ben ui's Resource for Unreal Engine</a></li>
<li><a href="https://wiki.planetchili.net/index.php/Chili_Framework" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chilli Tomato Noodles Planet Chilli Wiki for C++</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Check them out!</p>
<p>I plan to write about a variety of both systems and game development practices for Unreal Engine.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="unknown">Unknown<a href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome#unknown" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Unknown" title="Direct link to Unknown">​</a></h3>
<p>I have already got a lot of work ahead of me, but who knows? I may expand these plans into new areas or ideas as time goes on.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="suggestions">Suggestions<a href="https://gamedevforge.net/blog/Welcome#suggestions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Suggestions" title="Direct link to Suggestions">​</a></h2>
<p>As a community open source project, I hope as time goes on that the community can help me improve and grow this resource.
If you have any suggestions or ideas, comment on this post.</p>
<p>I look forward to hearing from you!</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Lewis Scrivens</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/lewisscrivens</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="Welcome" term="Welcome"/>
    </entry>
</feed>